Guide to the Alvin Roth Papers, 1960s-2000
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings by Others, 1973-1997 and undated, (2 boxes)
  - Gardner, Roy: n-Transfer Value and Fixed Price Equilibrium in Two-Sided Markets, 1983 (Box 19)
  - Harrington, Warren: The Genossenschaften, 1973 (Box 19)
  - Hart, Sergiu: Non-transferable Utility Games and Markets: Some Examples and the Harsanyi Sol. (Box 19)
  - Holt, Charles A.: The Effect of Market Power on the Direction of Convergence in Oral Double Auctions (Box 19)
  - Hughes, John S.: A Note on Stochastic Dominance and Preference, 1992 (Box 19)
  - Nalbantian, Haig: Matching and Efficiency in the Baseball Free-Agent System, 1991 (Box 19)
  - Shafer, Wayne J.: On Existence and Interpretation of Value Allocation, 1977 (Box 20)
  - Simon, Herbert: The Game of Chess (Box 20)
  - Sobolev, A.I.: The Characterization of Optimality Principles in Cooperative Games by Functional Equations, undated (Box 20)
  - Various authors: requests for feedback, 1997 and undated (Box 20)
- Teaching and Coursework, 1972-1980 and undated, (2 boxes)
  Lecture notes and transparencies from Roth's courses, including a mini-course of four lectures on game theory taught by Roth in 1980. Also includes coursework from Roth's time at Stanford.
  - Lecture notes on Nash and Utility of Bargaining, 1977 (Box 20)
  - Game theory class transparencies and notes (Box 20)
  - Transparencies with simple games, undated (Box 20)
  - Introduction to non-cooperative games, undated (Box 20)
  - Mini-course on Game Theory, 1980, (4 folders) (Box 20)
  - Analysis of Competitive Strategies, 1973 (Box 21)
  - Axiomatic Foundations of Choice Theory, 1972 (Box 21)
  - Class notes, undated (Box 21)
  - Coursework: Lattices, 1974 (Box 21)
  - Game theory notes, 1970s, (2 folders) (Box 21)
  - Microeconomics (Box 21)
  - Syllabi, bibliographies, and lecture notes, 1972-1976 (Box 21)
  - Game Theory reading list (Box 25)
- Grant Materials, 1988-1998, (1 boxes)
  Applications, correspondence, and financial materials from Roth's grant applications.
  - Alfred Sloan Foundation: Entry-level labor markets for elite professionals, 1988 (Box 26)
  - Russel Sage Foundation: Axiomatic Models of Bargaining, 1988 (Box 26)
  - NSF: Game-Theory Models of Bargaining, 1988-1989 (Box 26)
  - NSF: Coordination and operation of two-sided matching markets- theory and evidence, 1989 (Box 26)
  - NSF: Coordination and operation of two-sided matching model- theory and evidence, 1988-1990 (Box 26)
  - NIH: The Market for Physician Specialties, 1991, (3 folders) (Box 26)
  - NSF: Jumping the Gun: Intertemporal instability in two-sided matching and related markets, etc., 1992, (2 folders) (Box 26)
  - NSF: Low (rationality) Game Theory vs. High: experimental investigation of learning and adaptive behavior, 1995 (Box 26)
  - Citicorp: Performance, Pay, and Promotion: How Admin Procedures Interact with one Another, 1995 (Box 26)
  - NSF: Matching in Centralized and Decentralized Markets, 1995-1997, (2 folders) (Box 26)
  - NSF: Towards a Cognitive Game Theory, 1998 (Box 26)